# Zach **Schneider**

Software Developer

## Contact

#### **Address**

Parkesburg, PA, 19365

#### **Phone**

(419) 376-0273

#### E-mail

zachary.schneider85@gmail.com

#### www

https://zschneid85.github.io /devportfolio/

### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/zachschneider-5151aa1

## **Skills**

JavaScript	
Java	Very Good
Git	Excellent
HTML/CSS	Good
SQL	Excellent
WordPress	Excellent
PHP	Excellent
JQuery	Very Good
Bootstrap 4	Very Good

PROFILE Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

## **Work History**

### 2019-11 -

## **Lead Teacher**

Current

Wize Computing Academy, Exton, PA

- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional platforms Scratch, Lego wedo 2.0.
- Kept 15 students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Implemented lesson plans from start to finish with a Stem focused curriculum.

# 2018-08 -

# Current

# **Software Developer**

Zip Code Solutions, Parkesburg, PA

- Developing ,optimizing and maintaining websites and applications utilizing PHP, MySQL, Javascript, and various APIs to meet the goals of 30 plus clients.
- Created an Administrative backend so that clients can quickly update data by using databases.
- Migrating existing websites/applications to a stable, high-maintainable platform via AWS and WordPress.
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites.
- Prepared and presented technical proposals to clients focusing on needs.

# 2016-11 -

# 2018-03

# **Medicaid Billing Rep**

Conifer Health Solutions, Exton, PA

- Worked on 1,200 accounts per week with great attention to detail.
- Used a wide range of Medicaid billing tools to resolve a wide range of insurance denials.
- Produced \$150,000.00 per month in company revenue.

## **Education**

2018-03 -

## Certification of Completion: Software Development

2018-05

Rutgers University - New Brunswick

Coding Bootcamp

2004-08 -2008-05

Good

**Bachelor of Science: History** 

Eastern Michigan University - Ypsilanti, MI